Earlier, we learned about styles and how you can apply them
to an individual View. If you want to apply it to
all of the views in an activity or application, you can
do it by specifying a theme attribute on the activity or
application tag in the Android manifest. Now we style the action
bar to look like these visual mocks. This is the settings,
detail and main activity. For all cases, we want the background
color to be this blue hex color. Then we notice that the
styling of the settings and detail activities look very similar.
They both have the app icon and the activity title. On
the other hand, main activity just shows the logo. It's a
different attribute than the app icon, and this was provided in
asset drop earlier and it's called ic_logo. Because of these similarities,
we can use the same theme for these two activities and
we can create a new theme for the main activity. In
the case of our app, we use app theme here and
we use forecast theme here. We customize the themes in
the styles file in the base values folder. The app
theme inherits from the dark action bar system theme but
we override the action bar style to be our own.
This is defined here. We give it a parent ActionBar
style, and then we specify the background to be the
sunshine_blue color. Remember that this will be used in the
settings activity and the detail activity. Then for the main
activity, we declare the ForecastTheme. We inherit from the AppTheme, in
case there's more attributes that got added here, and then we'll be
able to inherit it for free. But we override the action bar
style to be this one. We set the logo because that's displayed
in the main activity, and we set the display options so
that we can show the logo. For more information on the action
bar display options, you can see the list here. For backward compatibility,
we needed to find these action bar styles in the base values
folder as well in the values V14 folder. The action bar compact class in the
support library handles action bar behavior up
through honeycomb. And then for ice cream sandwich
and above, it goes through the framework
implementation of the action bar. You can see
the code for the two files below. Go ahead and make these two changes now.